In the previous video, you learned about Git and GitHub. Before you continue with this video,
register for a GitHub account and log in. Let’s start by creating a new repository.
Click + then click New Repository. To create a new repository, you need to provide
these details: give your new repository a name; optionally, add a description of your repository;
choose the repository visibility - whether you want it to be public or private; and choose the option
to Initialize this repository with readme file. Then click Create Repository.
You will now be redirected to the repository you have created.
The root folder of your repository is listed by default and it has just one file ReadMe.md.
Now, it’s time to edit the readme. You can do this in your browser. Just click the pencil to open the
online editor and you can change the text of the readme. To save your changes to the repository,
you must commit them. After you have made your changes, scroll down to the Commit changes
section. Add a commit message and optionally add a description, then click Commit changes. The
"commit changes" is used to save your changes to the repository. Go back to the home screen by
clicking the repository name link. Note that the readme file is updated and verify your changes.
Let’s learn how to create a new file using the built-in web editor provided by GitHub which
runs in the browser. Click Add File, then click Create New File to create the new file.
To create a python file called firstpython.py.
First, provide the file name. Next, add a comment that describes your code, then add the code.
Once finished, commit the change to the repository. You can see that your file is
now added to the repository and the repository listing shows when the file was added or changed.
When you need to change the file, you can edit it again.
Click the file name, and then click the pencil icon, make your edits and commit the changes.
You can also upload a file from your local system into the repository.
From the home screen of the repository, click Add File and choose the Upload files option.
Click Choose Your Files and select the files you want to upload from your local system.
The file upload process may take a short time,
depending on what you are uploading. Once the files finish uploading,
click Commit Changes. The repository now reflects the files that were uploaded. In this video,
you learned how to create a repository, edit files, and commit changes using the web interface.